TRAN AI VAN

Date of birth: February 9, 1977

Address: 187/1 An Binh, District 5, Ho Chi Minh City

Mobile:

Email:



I have above 10+ years of experience in an IT Infrastructure environment. I am working as a National ICT Coordinator, and I have a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science. I am currently looking for an IT position and believe my work experience will make me a perfect candidate. I have a real passion for IT that combined with my always positive personality, I am convinced that I would make a good contribution to your company.

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

- Jan 2023 Present: SOS Children's Villages Vietnam Position: National ICT Coordinator
- Ensuring the operation of above 50 IT networks and providing nearly 300 co-workers and above 800 endpoints with technical support in order to access and work with the IT system.
- Planning, testing, and implementing an Asset management system to manage the assets of all the facilities.
- Implementing cloud-based Desktop and Mobile Device management tool Microsoft Intune.
- Enhancing system security by installing the Data encryption tool BitLocker and Installing antivirus SentinelOne.
- Configuring, managing, and monitoring Meraki network devices including Firewall, Switch, and Access Point.
- Equipping and installing firewall devices SafeGate School solution at Hermann Gmeiner School and Vocational Training Center.
- Installing CCTV Camera systems for all the facilities.
- Tracking, monitoring, and fixing security vulnerabilities to ensure information security for the entire system by Nessus, Meraki, PRTG, and Intune.
- Establishing scheduled tasks to backup data and system for emergency disaster recovery.
- Planning and monitoring IT budgets in the facilities.
- Searching, piloting, and deploying Action1 tools OS and Application vulnerability patching tools include Risk-based Patch Management, OS and Third-Party Patching, Software Deployment Remotely, Vulnerability Management, ect.
- Piloting, and deploying AnyConnect VPN tool to protect laptops using the Internet from outside the
 office.
- Planning, implementing, and monitoring Centralized log management tool.
- Providing Information Security training courses for Co-workers such as Security awareness, Identifying social engineering attacks, Sensitive data handling, Identifying and reporting incidents, etc.
- Developing IT security policies, procedures, and documents.
- Finding solutions to save costs.
- Dec 2019 Oct 2021: Al Power Company Position: IT Infrastructure & Helpdesk Leader
- Setting up a new office.
- Planning and building Network infrastructure.
- Configuring and managing Firewall equipment, and site-to-site VPN tunnel over the Internet.
- Configuring RADIUS Server for Wireless network.

- Establishing schedule tasks to backup data and system.
- Installing and managing Domain Controller, File Server, Virtual Machine Server...
- Installing Servers, security tools, and email systems.
- Enhancing system security by installing GPO, and Antivirus Server.
- Setting up laptops, desktops, and software for end users. Ensuring the security of data and network access.
- Setting up Print Server, Camera System, PABX system...
- Testing and piloting AI Fire Detection and Alert System with CCTV Cameras.
- Providing advanced support for special project requests, and serious problems.
- Analyzing user's requirements and proposing solutions.
- Consulting IT security policies, procedures, documents, and system integration.
- Dealing with ISP, suppliers to provide network connections and purchase IT equipment.

Aug 2011 – Oct 2019: Vietnam Food and Beverage Service Company (Dominos Pizza – Popeyes – BurgerKing)

Position: Deputy IT Manager (Network & System Infrastructure)

- Responsible for all IT infrastructure including the procurement, monitoring, and integration of all systems to achieve operation and stability.
- Planning and building Network infrastructure for Head office, Branches, and Restaurants.
- Planning and implementing Multisite Domain, Active Directory, and Group Policy.
- Installing and managing Domain Controller, Additional Domain Controller, Multi-Domain, File Server, Microsoft Exchange Server, Antivirus Server, Virtual Machine Server, Azure, and Radius Server.
- Configuring site-to-site VPN tunnel over the Internet (Over 100 sites).
- Working with ERP team to setup SAP server and go live SAP system.
- Establishing scheduled tasks to backup data and system for emergency disaster recovery.
- Coordinating with the vendor to install and improve the POS system and Web ordering system.
- Installing and controlling the ticket system.
- Providing end-users with assistance solving computer-related problems such as business software, hardware, system, network, and security.
- Installing network tools to monitor multisite networks and running regular checks on network and data security.
- Implementing centralization of fingerprint access control and fingerprint time attendance system.
- Building up the capability of the IT Department and other related departments by keeping them to stay up to date with digital technology developments and technology standards.
- Training and coaching team members on a new IT system.
- Developing IT security policies, procedures, and documents.

❖ Nov 2008 – Jul 2011: Indochina Airlines

<u>Position</u>: IT System & Network Manager

- Setting up and maintaining IT security policies.
- Planning and building Network infrastructure for Head office and Branch offices.
- Planning and implementing Active Directory.
- Installing and managing File Server, Mail Exchange Server, Web Server, etc.
- Implementing Firewall, Proxy, and VPN connection.
- Enhancing system security by installing Antivirus, WSUS.
- Managing and troubleshooting VoIP Contact Center to support Customer Service Center.
- Enforcing and controlling IT standards, policies, and procedures for security.

❖ Apr 2005 – Oct 2008: AVON Cosmetics Vietnam Company

Position: IT Specialist

• Setting up, maintaining, and improving network infrastructure.

- Configuring and managing Cisco routers, switches, and firewalls.
- Configuring secure wireless devices such as Linksys, and Cisco Access point.
- Enhancing system security by installing Antivirus, WSUS.
- Installing, managing, troubleshooting, and monitoring Windows 2003 Domain Controller, DNS, DHCP, FTP, File Server, Mail Lotus Notes, Printer Server, Remote Desktop, NAT, Radius Server.
- Collaborating with global to install and go live Microsoft Dynamics Axapta system.
- Maintaining and repairing computers and the PABX system.

❖ April 2004 – March 2005: Social Insurance Ho Chi Minh City Company Position: IT Specialist

- Enhancing system security and fault tolerance by installing server and client Antivirus (Symantec Antivirus), and patch management solutions for servers and workstations.
- Installing, maintaining, and monitoring Windows 2003 Active Directory Server, Printer Server, Microsoft Office ...
- Controlling all user accounts by creating and monitoring under a very tight policy.
- Supporting end-users to solve problems of software (Microsoft Office, Insurance software ...) and hardware (PCs, Fax, Printer...).
- Repairing computer hardware and installing software.

❖ November 2002 – March 2004: Railway Communication Signal Saigon Company Position: IT Officer

- Supporting end users to solve problems of software (Microsoft Office, Switchboard Software) and hardware (PCs, Fax, Printer, PABX ...).
- Repairing computer hardware and installing software.
- Solving applications related to problems.
- Programming PABX.

QUALIFICATIONS:

- Certified Web Developer Frontend (HTML, JavaScript, React, WordPress) and Backend (Nodejs, Python) of Matrix Master Academy in The Netherlands.
- Bachelor's degree in computer science of Ho Chi Minh City Open University in Vietnam.
- Certified MCITP-EA (equivalent MCSE) of Microsoft.
- Certified CCNA of Cisco.
- Certified JRMS & RMSWEB (POS System) of STMPI Corporation.

SKILLS:

- Expert in operating systems, network configuration and repair computer hardware.
- Experience in Multisite Domain, Active Directory, Group Policy.
- Master in cloud system such as Microsoft Office 365, Azure, Intune, etc.
- Good experience with virtualizing technology (VMWare Server, Hyper-V).
- Strong working knowledge storage.
- Mail Server Systems: MS Exchange Server 2013 & 2016, MDaemon, and G-Suite.
- Strong deploying Security system solutions, and Anti-Virus server solutions such as Centralized log management, Data loss preventions (DLP), Vulnerability scanning, TrendMicro, Trellix, SentinelOne, ect
- Excellent working knowledge of backup software like Symantec Backup Exec, and Veeam backup.
- Database: MS SQL Server 2016, and MongoDB.
- Strong understanding with PABX, Ticket system, Access control, Fire alarm.
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Nodejs, WordPress, React.

LANGUAGES:

- Vietnamese: native speaking.
- English: Intermediate.

ABILITIES:

- Hard-working, responsible, and patient.
- Work under pressure and challenges.
- Strong teamwork, organization, and priority skills.
- Able to demonstrate a high level of integrity and initiative.